I'm not going to lie, at this point you have every reason to be impatient with me.
솔직히 지금 저한테 짜증 낼 이유가 충분하죠
We've been yammering away for ages about raga, and you've not actually had a chance to use rag yet.
우린 라가 얘기를 한참 했는데 아직 라가를 써 본 적이 없네요
We've just talked about vectors.
벡터에 대해 얘기했죠
We've talked about prompts and context and cheap versions of Rag.
프롬프트와 컨텍스트 래그의 저렴한 버전에 관해 얘기했죠
Finally, it's time for the real deal.
드디어 본격적인 시작이죠
Today, it's time that we put a rag pipeline into action.
오늘은 Put 파이프라인을 실행할 거예요
And it's going to be stupid.
바보 같은 짓이죠
Easy.
진정해요
Just you wait.
두고 봐요
So what's going to happen today?
오늘은 어떻게 될까요?
We're going to create a conversation chain in long chain, which is where long chain comes together
긴 사슬로 된 대화 사슬을 만들 거예요 긴 사슬이 모여서
to put the different pieces glued together to give you a conversation with retrieval with Rag.
여러 조각을 접착제로 붙이는 거죠 걸레 회수와 대화를 할 수 있게요
We're going to ask questions and get answers that demonstrate an expert understanding and will build
전문가의 이해를 보여주는 질문을 하고 답을 얻을 겁니다 채팅 UI로 궁극적으로
ultimately a knowledge worker assistant with a chat UI.
지식 작업자 비서를 만들고요
And because of all the wonderful things that you've already learned, you're going to see that it's
이미 훌륭한 것들을 배웠기 때문에 아주
going to be incredibly easy, of course.
쉽다는 걸 알게 될 거예요
So first of all, just to give you a briefing, there are some abstractions in long chain, some some
먼저 간략히 말씀드리자면 긴 연결의 추상화가 있어요 긴 연결의
concepts that long chain has defined that make things easier.
개념이 일을 쉽게 만들어주죠
And here are the three of them that we will be using today.
이건 오늘 사용할 3가지예요
First of all, there's an abstraction around an LLM.
우선 LLM에는 추상적인 게 있어요
An LLM is just represents, in our case, OpenAI.
LLM은 오픈아이를 의미해요
But it could represent others.
다른 사람을 상징할 수도 있죠
And Liangcheng gives you that one object that represents your abstraction around a model.
량청은 모델을 둘러싼 추상적인 객체를 대표해요
Then there is an abstraction called a retriever.
레트리버라는 추상화도 있어요
And that is a sort of interface onto something like a vector store.
벡터 스토어 같은 인터페이스 같은 거죠
In our case, it will be Cromer, which will be used for Rag retrieval.
우리 경우엔 크로머예요 걸레 회수용으로 사용되죠
So that is a retriever interface around something that can take vectors and can enrich your prompt.
벡터를 가지고 프롬프트를 강화할 수 있는 레트리버 인터페이스죠
And then the third abstraction is memory.
세 번째 추상화는 메모리예요
And that represents some kind of a of a history of a discussion with a chatbot in some way, some memory.
챗봇과 토론한 역사를 보여주는 거죠 어떤 식으로든 메모리요
So this in practice, what we're used to here is that list of dicts, that list that comprises of a
실제로 여기서 사용되는 건 독감 목록이에요 상단의 시스템 메시지 같은 걸
sort of a system message at the top, and then user assistant, user assistant.
구성한 목록이죠 다음은 사용자 보조예요
But that has been abstracted away into a concept called memory for long chain, which behind under the
하지만 긴 연결을 위한 메모리라는 개념으로 추출되었어요. 이 커버 아래에서 리스트를
covers it will handle that list or whatever other kind of format different models might need.
처리하거나 다른 모델이 필요로 하는 다른 형식을 처리하죠.
So these are the three key, uh, wrappers around more functionality that you get from long Chain.
이 세 가지가 핵심 래퍼입니다. Get-Tuck Season 2 닙턱 시즌 2 긴 체인에서 얻는 기능성 중에서요.
And with that in mind, take a look at how simple it's going to be to put together a rag pipeline.
이것을 명심하고 얼마나 간단한지 보세요. Get 파이프라인을 만드는 것이요.
It's going to be done with four lines of code.
4줄의 코드로 완료될 거예요
And here are the four lines of code in front of you right now.
지금 여러분 앞에 있는 코드 4줄이에요
And this is the brilliance that is in the first line.
첫 번째 줄의 우수함이 이거예요
LM is chat open AI that is creating a lang chain ln object.
LM은 채팅방개 인공지능으로 랑 체인 ln 객체를 생성하죠
LM object for open AI.
개방형 인공지능을 위한 LM 객체죠
And you can imagine there's similar objects that you could create for anything else.
다른 어떤 것을 위해 만들 수 있는 비슷한 오브젝트가 있다고 상상할 수 있죠
That's the first line, the first abstraction.
그게 첫 번째 줄이자 첫 번째 추상화예요
LM the second line.
두 번째 줄에 LM을 넣어요
The second abstraction.
두 번째 추상화요
Memory.
메모리 말이에요
You create a lang chain object called a conversation buffered memory.
대화 버퍼 메모리라는 랑 체인 객체를 생성해요
You have to provide this a couple of things.
몇 가지 사항을 제공해야 해요
The key is just the the how it will organize, what it will, what you can use to look up that memory
핵심은 어떻게 정리되느냐죠 메모리와 채팅 기록을 검색하는 데 뭘 쓸 수 있느냐예요
and chat history is what it has to be, because that's what's going to be expected later and return
나중에 예상되는 게 그거니까요 반송 메시지는 랭에게 이걸
messages is telling Lang that you're going to want this to be stored in a way that what comes back are
저장할 거라고 말해요 일련의 메시지로 저장될 거라고요
going to be a series of messages, not just a big block of text representing the conversation.
대화를 나타내는 큰 텍스트 블록 말고요
So you just need to know that these are what you have to use for this kind of chat application.
이런 종류의 채팅 응용 프로그램에 이걸 사용해야 한다는 것만 아시면 돼요
The next line is quite simply saying we have a vector store that we've created its chroma, and we're
다음 줄은 간단히 벡터 스토어가 있는데 크로마를 생성했고 이것을 불러오기
going to call this this this method as retriever.
메서드로 부르겠다고 하네요
And it's going to wrap that in an interface object called a retriever.
레트리버라는 인터페이스 객체로 감싸게 되죠
And that is the the kind of, uh, object that Lang chain is expecting in order to be able to, to have
그게 랭 체인이 기대하는 객체예요 래그 워크플로우가 가능하려면요
So those are our three abstractions the LM, the memory and the retriever.
세 가지 추상화입니다 LM, 메모리 그리고 리트리버죠
They've all been created.
전부 만들어진 거예요
And now that last line puts it together into something called a conversation chain.
마지막 구절은 그걸 하나로 모아 대화 사슬을 형성해요
Uh, and that is something which is a conversation retrieval chain that you create, uh, and you call,
그건 여러분이 만든 대화 회수 사슬로 호출을, 그 음 LM으로부터의
you create it by calling that, that, um, uh, method from LM, and you just pass in three things
메서드를 호출해 생성합니다 여러분은 3가지만 넘기면 돼요
the LM, the retriever and the memory, the three things we just created.
LM, 레트리버, 메모리 방금 만든 3가지요
And so it's as simple as that.
그렇게 간단한 거예요
With that fourth line of code, we have just created a Rag pipeline.
코드 네 번째 줄로 방금 래그 파이프라인을 만들었어요
You don't believe me?
못 믿겠어요?
Let's go over to JupyterLab and give it a try ourselves.
유피터랩으로 가서 직접 해 보죠